<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits</title>
    <link>https://ivylee.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ivylee&#34;&gt;Ivy Lee&lt;/a&gt; 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 13:47:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ivylee.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>training monitoring with Visdom and Hyperdash</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/training-monitoring-visdom-hyperdash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 13:47:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/training-monitoring-visdom-hyperdash/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, I have enjoyed using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebookresearch/visdom&#34;&gt;Visdom&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperdash.io&#34;&gt;Hyperdash&lt;/a&gt; to monitor training processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visdom&#34;&gt;Visdom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visom is a Python library developed by Facebook Research. Similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/summaries_and_tensorboard&#34;&gt;Tensorboard&lt;/a&gt;,
it provides a UI server (using React) through which user can create scatter plots, histograms, visualize images and text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written a small snippet for creating and updating a scatter plot,
which can be used for visualizing training and validation loss and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# pip install visdom numpy
# visualize.py
import numpy
from visdom import Visdom

class Plot(object):
    def __init__(self, title, port=8080):
        self.viz = Visdom(port=port)
        self.windows = {}
        self.title = title

    def register_scatterplot(self, name, xlabel, ylabel):
        win = self.viz.scatter(
            X=numpy.zeros((1, 2)),
            opts=dict(title=self.title, markersize=5, xlabel=xlabel, ylabel=ylabel)
        )
        self.windows[name] = win

    def update_scatterplot(self, name, x, y):
        self.viz.updateTrace(
            X=numpy.array([x]),
            Y=numpy.array([y]),
            win=self.windows[name]
        )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my training script, I can initialize and update the plots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# train.py
import visualize

plot = visualize.Plot(&amp;quot;Model A&amp;quot;)
plot.register_scatterplot(&amp;quot;Loss&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Epoch&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Loss&amp;quot;)
for n in range(epoch):
    # ... compute average loss over training data
    plot.update_scatterplot(&amp;quot;Loss&amp;quot;, n + 1, loss)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before running the training script, we need to start the web server, so that after training starts,
we can go to &lt;code&gt;localhost:8080&lt;/code&gt; in the browser to see the plots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;python -m visdom.server -p 8080
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above snippets can also be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ivylee/b2f47d1ad787d7f7079c596bb0ac9c0f&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pytorch/tnt&#34;&gt;PyTorchNet&lt;/a&gt; library provides more &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pytorch/tnt/blob/master/torchnet/logger/visdomlogger.py&#34;&gt;loggers&lt;/a&gt; for plots, images, and text, it can be very handy if you&amp;rsquo;re a PyTorch user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hyperdash&#34;&gt;Hyperdash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visdom is great for visualizing plots and images, however connection to a remote server isn&amp;rsquo;t always available.
Hyperdash can stream training logs from a process on a remote server directly to my phone.
I can simply open the mobile app to know if the training process died, or loss is no longer decreasing.
The set up is quite simple, all necessary steps are documented in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hyperdash.io&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;.
One caveat is that it does not work well with &lt;code&gt;tqdm&lt;/code&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hyperdashio/hyperdash-sdk-py/issues/63&#34;&gt;issue 63&lt;/a&gt;), simply disable &lt;code&gt;tqdm&lt;/code&gt; in the training script.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a minimal training plot server</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/a-minimal-training-plot-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 16:15:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/a-minimal-training-plot-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Training a deep convolutional neural network (CNN) can be a lengthy process.
We usually want to monitor training loss and accuracy and validation loss and accuracy by plotting how these metrics
change as the number of minibatches grows on a graph.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org&#34;&gt;Tensorflow&lt;/a&gt; provides &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/get_started/summaries_and_tensorboard&#34;&gt;Tensorboard&lt;/a&gt; for visualizing training progress.
Recently I have been playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://pytorch.org&#34;&gt;PyTorch&lt;/a&gt;, I really like its expresiveness and flexibility.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a strategy for visualizing training progress with
any learning framework that doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide Tensorboard-equivalent feature out of the box using Python 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all as a good practice we output relevant metrics into a log file, the log file should be structured in a way
that is easy to parse and extract metrics. We will need to write a parser method, and a plot method to generate desired
graph(s). &lt;a href=&#34;http://matplotlib.org&#34;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://seaborn.pydata.org&#34;&gt;seaborn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ggplot.yhathq.com&#34;&gt;ggplot&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://bokeh.pydata.org/en/latest&#34;&gt;bokeh&lt;/a&gt; are useful python libraries for graphing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/asyncio.html&#34;&gt;asyncio&lt;/a&gt; to create a background job to plot the metrics we want to visualize and use &lt;a href=&#34;http://aiohttp.readthedocs.io/en/stable&#34;&gt;aiohttp&lt;/a&gt; to create
a web server that displays and refreshes the graph(s) at a certain interval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Using python 3.4
import asyncio
import argparse
from aiohttp import web


GRAPH_LOCATION = &amp;quot;static/train_plot.png&amp;quot;


def parser(log_file):
    # read log_file and extract metrics such as
    # minibatch number, training loss, training accuracy,
    # validation loss, validation accuracy
    return metrics


def plot(metrics, output=GRAPH_LOCATION):
    # save output image to GRAPH_LOCATION


def plot_loop(args, loop):
    print(&amp;quot;Updating plot&amp;quot;)
    metrics = parser(args.log_file)
    plot(metrics)
    loop.call_later(args.interval, plot_loop, args, loop)


@asyncio.coroutine
def handler(request):
    interval = int(request.GET.get(&#39;interval&#39;, 30))
    resp = web.StreamResponse(status=200,
                              reason=&#39;OK&#39;,
                              headers={&#39;Content-Type&#39;: &#39;text/html&#39;})

    yield from resp.prepare(request)

    html_str = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;
        &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&#39;refresh&#39; content=&#39;{}&#39;&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
                &amp;lt;img src=&#39;{}&#39; width=&#39;100%&#39;/&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
    &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;.format(interval, GRAPH_LOCATION)
    resp.write(str.encode(html_str))

    yield from resp.drain()
    return resp


@asyncio.coroutine
def build_server(loop, address, port):
    app = web.Application(loop=loop)
    app.router.add_route(&#39;GET&#39;, &amp;quot;/plot&amp;quot;, handler)
    app.router.add_static(&#39;/static&#39;, &amp;quot;static&amp;quot;)
    ret = yield from loop.create_server(app.make_handler(), address, port)
    return ret


if __name__ == &amp;quot;__main__&amp;quot;:
    parser = argparse.ArgumentParser(description=&#39;Training graphs server&#39;)
    parser.add_argument(&#39;log_file&#39;,
                        help=&#39;path to train log file&#39;)
    parser.add_argument(&#39;--interval&#39;, &#39;-i&#39;, default=30,
                        help=&#39;plot interval&#39;)
    parser.add_argument(&#39;--port&#39;, &#39;-p&#39;, default=7777,
                        help=&#39;server port&#39;)
    args = parser.parse_args()

    loop = asyncio.get_event_loop()
    loop.call_soon(plot_loop, args, loop)
    loop.run_until_complete(build_server(loop, &#39;0.0.0.0&#39;, args.port))
    try:
        loop.run_forever()
    except KeyboardInterrupt:
        print(&amp;quot;Server shutting down!&amp;quot;)
        loop.close()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This snippet can also be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/ivylee/f1b00ce54f948e627605598ccf3cf4b9&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>in guangzhou</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/in-guangzhou/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 04:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/in-guangzhou/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m back after spending the last 3 years in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still a bit jet-lagged, I went for my visa interview today and finished within half an hour,
while watching lines of people slowly moving, occasionally one or two arguing with the assistants.
There&amp;rsquo;s so much heat, it makes the people short-tempered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the subway home as I vaguely remember how to get there from this station.
To make sure I studied the map, and found a few more new lines but the way home didn&amp;rsquo;t change.
One stop before the transfer I decided to go out and walk back along the river.
There it is, a new tram! A cute little tram that travels only within a short distance.
Walking on, I discovered plenty of seniors and kids with nannies enjoying their day,
and an open-air ballroom under the bridge where the dancing and the music happen.
It&amp;rsquo;s definitely much more crowded and full of life compared to when I first moved in to this neighborhood,
about 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than anything else, I miss the food here.
I tried rice noodles with Shantou beef balls in a neighborhood restaurant yesterday with my mother,
it was awesome. I also made sure to eat curry fish balls from 7-11 that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find in any 7-11 in the US.
The old and trusted restaurants are still around, with plenty of new and upcoming competitors.
But the prices seem to be 20% higher than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banking and mobile services are disappointing, for anyone spoiled by the efficiency of the US.
I spent more than 2 hours in the bank to do something that need not to be done ever in the US.
I visited 3 stores just to find out the prepaid plans I saw online are not available in store,
because of lower margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(To be continued&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ghost easy upgrade</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/ghost-easy-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 02:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/ghost-easy-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost is a really nice blogging solution. I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated my blog for such a long time and I am surprised to find out how easy the upgrade process is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the latest Ghost zip bundle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unzip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into the unzipped directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rm -rf content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;copy config.js and content from previous version Ghost directory to here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm install &amp;ndash;production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm start :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope buster still works&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lessons learned about jalapeño</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/lessons-learned-about-jalapeno/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 18:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/lessons-learned-about-jalapeno/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is hot.
Cut it using a fork, instead of fixing it with your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were cooking vegetables with tofu yesterday. As usual Julio likes to add a Jalapeño into the mix. I cut it the way I cut other vegetables, using my fingers to fix it while cutting it with a knife. About 5 minutes later, I started to feel very hot in my nails. I went to the bathroom to wash my hands with soap, and accidentally touched my nostrils with my fingers. I felt it burning in my nose! And my nails! Soap doesn&amp;rsquo;t help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hot sensation lasted until this morning. I also accidentally touched my eyes with my fingers, HOT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am facinated by the power of the chemical substance in the Jalapeño pepper, and the fact that finger nails, nostrils, eyes can react the same way to that substance by generating the HOT sensation, just as the tongue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will remember Julio said that his mother cuts it with a fork, no touching with fingers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>after a long hiatus</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/after-a-long-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 04:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/after-a-long-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to write again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first I needed to migrate my blog from Octopress to Ghost.
I was happy with Octopress until I discovered every update/push took forever because I have 200+ posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migration was not easy. Took me almost 4 nights. Essentially the problems for me were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t push the markdown files that are supposed to be under &lt;code&gt;source/_posts&lt;/code&gt; to github.
So I only have a bunch of published html files waiting to be converted back to markdown.
During conversion it&amp;rsquo;s tricky to deal with Chinese characters, took me 1-2 nights to figure out.
Loading Octopress markdown files to Ghost database. There&amp;rsquo;s a nice script available however some tweaks were needed to suit my use case.
I decided not to integrate Disqus comments for now. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I still have your previous comments in heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ivylee/octoghost&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; repo if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering whether my experience might be helpful to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I like the combination of &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/axitkhurana/buster&#34;&gt;Buster&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;
as described &lt;a href=&#34;https://jackpearce.com/have-a-lightning-fast-blog-and-host-it-for-free&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; :) And I&amp;rsquo;m writing again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Programming First Class</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/parallel-programming-first-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/parallel-programming-first-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I took a taste of Parallel Programming course from CS dept,
expecting it to be about achieving parallelization using a low-level
language like C/C++ with intensive knowledge on computer theory etc.,
however it turned out to be lectured by a researcher at IBM who
introduced a language, X10, built on top of Java, with functional
programming concept as in Scala. As X10 focuses on concurrency there’s
new types and ‘struct’ as in C/C++. By using a simple example the class
discussed common problems arise in concurrent computation, as appeared
in using Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on what I’ve learned today it seems the advantage of X10 is
concurrency without the limitation of map-reduce paradigm. However X10
is still under development, and seemed to be only used at IBM. Its
popularity should increase by time, especially for tasks that are found
to be difficult to tackle with Hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference: &lt;a href=&#34;http://x10-lang.org/&#34;&gt;http://x10-lang.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download List of Files With Bash and Wget in Command Line</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/download-list-of-files-with-bash-and-wget-in-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/download-list-of-files-with-bash-and-wget-in-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to download a list of lecture slides from course page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;for i in {11..19}; do wget -r -l1 http://someurl/slides_lecture$i.pdf;done;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspect the url structure first. Easier to write one line of code than
to create a general script.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Panic</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/dont-panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/dont-panic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is probably the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_Panic_(The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy)&#34;&gt;best
advice&lt;/a&gt;
given to human race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it seemed the city was overreacting. Shutting down public
transportation, stopping schools, gathering food and water. All this,
seemed unreal until I lost electricity at around 8.30 pm Oct. 29th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few minutes before that, I had my tv turned on, following the news while
I had dinner. A man in uniform knocked on my door and asked if I had
opened my windows since there were some strange noise and other
residents complained. Of course I didn’t open my windows and I heard the
noise too! Fortunately I wasn’t the only one that found the noise
unpleasant. I grabbed a notice on the door handle regarding the storm as
he left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as I was going to clean up, after a flash everything went dark. Oh,
power outage hit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have my flash light prepared, because I never thought I’d be
using it. After a while scrambling over my drawers in the dark, I
managed to find my small carry-around flash light but no batteries. But
I knew I brought one with me from China. So all I had to do was look
again, this time more carefully. Then I found one, and another one. But
getting a flash light didn’t help. I could do nothing about the
electricity. I went out to the hall way, all the emergency lights on,
and nobody was there. It was quiet. I guessed nobody panicked, which was
great. Then I came back, wondering what I could do. I dialed the numbers
on the notice and confirmed the whole building was in power outage and
there was no news about when it would come back. I looked outside the
window, funny thing was I could see the border of power outage, just
right across the street. On the left everything was dark, on the right
everything lit up. And police cars were rushing towards the
neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t study, which was what I planned for the night. I had to save
the laptop battery, it was charged about 100%. I got the Powerbank, also
from China, to charge my phone. I sent msgs with friends and family, did
the trash, washed the dishes, showered and flossed before going to bed
with sirens and lights outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 3 am I woke up, it was still noisy. It is always noisy here, sirens
roaring from 11 pm till midnight all the way through morning. I tried
the lamp, still dark anyway. Then I went back to sleep, hoping things
would work in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 8.40 am, I got up and tried the lights, still the same. I still
had hot water, everything except electricity. My stove wasn’t working. I
had to think about my food. Luckily without planning for emergency, I
had bread, milk, orange juice, tomatoes, cucumbers, bananas and green
grapes, all of which could be consumed without cooking. But I’d like my
milk to be warm. The solution was filling the stockpot with hot tap
water and put my mug with milk in. So I had a nice breakfast as usual,
warm milk and a banana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dialed the numbers on the notice again, no news for power recovery. I
had to figure out what to do for a whole day and worry about getting to
school tomorrow if subway service was still suspended. About 6.5 hrs of
battery left on my laptop. So I wrote this post and then started reading
the textbook to prepare for midterm on Thursday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around noon, I noticed water coming out of my tap much more slower than
usual. Worried that I might run out of it, I saved some using pans and
anything that seemed to be capable of storing water. About half an hour
later, the nightmare happened. No electricity, no water. I couldn’t even
flush the toilet. One can live without electricity but NOT without
water! This was the moment that I really panicked. I needed a place to
live! Survive! I had to abandon my apt! I tried to call management
office to confirm the water outage, but they didn’t seem to know what
was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very lucky. After posting on facebook and a few text msgs, I had
options of places to stay. I had been very lucky since I came to New
York. Life is an adventure. You’ll never know where it takes you,
especially in face of disaster and uncertainty. I’d never thought the
following days would turn out to be one of the happiest week of my life,
the happiest I could be in the shadow of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left my apt in the afternoon of Oct 30th, came back in the morning of
Nov 4th. I might have been the luckiest and happiest refugee. Everything
looked intact. All I needed to do was some cleaning, and life went back
to normal. I did have a secret small wish that I could stay longer as a
refugee. But life goes on! And life is better now that I have all those
warm and happy memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C’est la vie. C’est ma vie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With SAS on Columbia Unix Server</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/working-on-columbia-unix-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/working-on-columbia-unix-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m taking two courses that use SAS this semester because SAS is rather
widely used in industry. But it’s expensive and few students taking the
same classes ever talked about buying the licence. So I have to use SAS
on unix server, and this is rather painful experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSH into unix server is not a problem, but Kerberos authentication
keeps asking for password whenever a connection is made, which means
when SSH into the unix server and exchanging files between remote
and local. having to type password over and over again is nightmare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SAS version on unix server is quite old, 9.1.3 compared to 9.2 in
computer labs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the GUI of SAS unix can be launched by ssh -X, but it depends on the
xserver of local, and I don’t like the experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some command line options better be added when running SAS on
remote, to suppress unnecessary logging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the SAS licence own by Columbia is expiring in about a month, SAS
keeps popping warning messages in log file and there is no way to
suppress them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address problem 1, solution I found so far is to obtain a Kerberos
ticket valid for 10 hours so one does not have to enter password for a
period of time, but it’s not a thorough solution due to the nature of
Kerberos, there’s no way to avoid entering password forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is only tested on Mac OS X 10.8.2, solution should be
similiar on Unix/Linux machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ scp [uni]@cunix.cc.columbia.edu:/etc/krb5.conf ~/

$ sudo mv ~/krb5.conf /etc/
$ sudo vim /etc/krb5.conf
    # add the following in [libdefaults] section
    forward = true
    forwardable = true
    renewable = true
  :wq

$ vim ~/.ssh/config
    # add the following lines
    GSSAPIAuthentication yes
    GSSAPIDelegateCredentials yes
  :wq

$ kinit [uni] # enter password
$ klist # to check ticket status
$ ssh [uni]@cunix.cc.columbia.edu # should connect without prompting password
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make life easier, add some shortcuts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ vim ~/.bashrc
    alias cussh=&#39;ssh [uni]@cunix.cc.columbia.edu&#39;
    export unixhome=[uni]@cunix.cc.columbia.edu:[$home location]
  :wq

# login to remote server
$ cussh
# uploading
$ scp [local files] $unixhome/[remote location]
# downloading
$ scp $unixhome/[remote files] [local]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each ticket is only valid for 10 hrs, which is a parameter set on
Kerberos server. Ticket can be renewed before expiration by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ kinit -R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ref &amp;amp; further info:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/kerberos/krb5-current/doc/krb_users/tkt_mgmt.html&#34;&gt;Kerberos
doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://weblion.psu.edu/trac/weblion/wiki/KerberizeYourSshClient&#34;&gt;Kerbenize ssh
client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ugcs.caltech.edu/Kerberized_SSH.xhtml&#34;&gt;kinit automatically when
necessary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://coxmanagement.wordpress.com/2012/05/07/kerberos-authentication-under-lion/&#34;&gt;Kerberos with PAM under
Lion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For problem 2 and 3, stop by computer labs to use SAS 9.2 on Windows
machine with GUI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some options to supply on command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sas -nodms -nonews [program.sas]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other options to put in *.sas file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;options nodate nonumber nocenter ls=70 ps=80;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for problem 5, hopefully Columbia will upgrade SAS to 9.2 or 9.3.
Just see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptron</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/my-first-machine-learning-algo-perceptron/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 10:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/my-first-machine-learning-algo-perceptron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To me, a novice programmer, understanding the algorithm is much more
easier than writing it. This is my first homework assignment of the Data
Mining/Machine Learning course I’m taking this semester, taught by
Professor &lt;a href=&#34;http://stat.columbia.edu/~porbanz/&#34;&gt;Peter Orbanz&lt;/a&gt; . The
perceptron algorithm is a simple idea for linear classification. R is
really handy :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check out the perceptron algorithm, including both batch
perceptron and fix increment single sample perceptron, in my github repo
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ivylee/machine-learning&#34;&gt;machine-learning&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalistic Resume Template</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/my-resume-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/my-resume-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here I am. Just arrive, getting used to New York, excited about new life
and new things to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LaTeX is very nice for writing structured documents. I used to prepare
my resume using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctan.org/pkg/moderncv&#34;&gt;moderncv&lt;/a&gt; . It was
really nice, easy and beautiful. But somehow I find it a little bit too
fancy now. I decided to write my own resume class, no coloring no
pictures just plain and simple. I used LaTeX for my undergraduate thesis
and I modified thesis templates from other sources to fit my thesis
format requirements, but I’ve never build a template from ground up
myself. So the resume template, it was good exercise. Now I’m not scared
of writing LaTeX class files anymore. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Btw it’s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ivylee/latex/blob/master/my_resume.cls&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>重複的夢</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/repeated-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/repeated-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;某種記憶是一組相連的神經元，當大腦已經遺忘的時候，會突然出現，熟悉又完整。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;前天的夢：牙齒脫落&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;睡眠中突然有意識，很驚恐，手一碰右邊門牙和門牙右邊那顆牙，它們就掉了，有點疼，又不是特別疼，繼續很驚恐，到處求助如何把牙安上去或者裝假牙，在驚恐中回憶起以前曾做過這樣的夢，但是同樣不知所措，在驚恐焦慮中又睡着了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;今天的夢：北韓間諜活動&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;睡眠中，意識出現，我，我父母，我的一個女同學，在一個北韓鄉村顯要人物家裏受邀吃飯，緊張的氣氛。我意識到自己曾經做過這個夢，而且結局是鄉村顯要人物家庭一位女性年長成員死了並且屍體送到我以前的住處，於是我努力想改變結局，要在夢中嘗試不同的做法。我想幫助那位年長的成員，她可能是僕人，可能是家中長輩，她喪命的原因是那位鄉村顯要發現我們是間諜而我們又幫助了那位年長女性。於是我決定，同樣地，要幫助那位女性，而且要在別人下手前保護她。在餐桌上，正如上一次夢境，緊張有序地進食，我作出的改變是提示同學和我一起到廚房幫助那位年長女性準備食材。在廚房我們與她交談，她略顯緊張，但也接受我們的幫助，僅僅是準備食材而已。飯局結束，我意識到那位年長女性即將性命不保，敦促家人趕緊回家，以防年長女性在我們家裏被殺害留下血跡作爲對我們的震懾。內心緊張外表鎮定從容地趕路，路上我靈機一動買了一大桶灰色塑料包裝的漿糊，和一桶白色油漆，必要時可以把門粘起來作爲抵抗。到家上樓時，見到一個大紙皮箱，可裝入一個人那種，還有兩位快遞人員等候我們簽收。我心裏很害怕，怕還是遲來了一步。誰知道，簽收時，包裹裏竟然是另一個男人的屍體，一個我們沒有印象的人。猶豫了一陣，我安慰自己，幸好不是她，正在想接下來怎麼辦時，電鑽響了我醒了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;經常在夢中，我意識到自己在做夢，並且用自己的意志去改變夢境，而不是由夢引導自己的思想。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>不務正業理想課程</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/ideal-coursework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/ideal-coursework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;話說多年來與母上聊天過程中，提到過幾種非傳統教育涉及的職業及專業培訓，很驚喜地在與好友阿靚聊天過程中，找回對那些專業培訓的嚮往，簡單列舉，日後希望有機會嘗試完成：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;廚藝課程（即使修成不夠開餐館，也有能力填飽自己）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;調酒師課程 Bar-tendering （因爲自己喜歡 cocktail,
大一曾學習過相關課程，礙於學業未能繼續，甚爲遺憾。有此專業訓練可成爲
Bar tender, 甚至創業開酒吧）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;咖啡師 （亦在大一參與的課程學習過相關知識）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;評酒師（要求敏感的味覺，母上覺得我可以）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;調香師（敏感的嗅覺）（以上兩者我暫時未知道有確實的課程）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;壽司學徒（喜愛壽司，以及其製作的過程。向喜愛壽司的朋友推薦紀錄片：《壽司之神》）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一向接受傳統教育的我，感覺到缺乏對某種事物無止境的熱情。希望將來我能夠有時間和能力，追求一種屬於自己熱愛的可以不斷練習鑽研的東西。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colors</title>
      <link>https://ivylee.github.io/post/colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivylee.github.io/post/colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天突然间超级无聊，折腾起 Bash prompt 和 dircolors…=_= 不喜欢
solarized, 也不喜欢 Ubuntu
默认的紫色低白字，duckduckgo&amp;amp;google了一轮才明白 Bash prompt
用那么奇怪的颜色代号，和只有那么少的颜色，而且是 gnome-terminal profile
设置的颜色。dircolors支持256colors，把颜色全部列出来一个个看顺眼才写进配置里真累…..折腾完觉得好看多了，可是，好，无，聊，啊，我！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;反正现在都 zenburn 了，以后也懒得再弄。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;另外 Bash 好难&amp;gt;_&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;好久没写东西一写居然是此等无聊之作，好无聊…流离失所的无奈&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>